It ain't over 'til it's over.
Rocky Balboa is a drama film directed by Sylvester Stallone.
When he loses a highly publicized virtual boxing match to ex-champ Rocky Balboa, reigning heavyweight
titleholder Mason Dixon retaliates by challenging the Italian Stallion to a 10-round exhibition bout.
To the surprise of his son and friends, Rocky agrees to come out of retirement and
face an opponent who's faster, stronger and thirty years his junior.
Rocky takes on Dixon in what will become the greatest fight in boxing history!
Robert 'Rocky' Balboa, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Paulie Pennino, played by Burt Young.
Mason 'The Line' Dixon, played by Antonio Tarver.
Marie, played by Geraldine Hughes.
Robert 'Rocky' Balboa Jr., played by Milo Ventimiglia.
Tony 'Duke' Evers, played by Tony Burton.
Rocky Balboa is a 2006 American sports drama film starring,
written and directed by Sylvester Stallone.
It is the sequel to Rocky V (1990) and the sixth
installment in the Rocky franchise.
The film co-stars Burt Young and Antonio Tarver in his only acting role.
In the film, Rocky Balboa (Stallone), now an aging small restaurant owner, is
challenged to an exhibition fight by hothead young boxer Mason Dixon (Tarver).
Development for a sixth Rocky film began after Stallone expressed regret over the outcome
of Rocky V, which was viewed as a disappointing conclusion to the series.
Rocky Balboa includes references to characters and objects from previous installments, and
Stallone was inspired by recent personal struggles and triumphs when writing the film.
It is Stallone's first directorial effort since Rocky IV (1985).
Principal photography began in December 2005 and lasted until January 2006, with
filming locations including Las Vegas, Los Angeles, and Philadelphia.
In contrast to previous entries in the franchise, the fight choreography in Rocky Balboa
was less scripted, featuring real punches thrown by Stallone and Tarver.
It was produced by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, Columbia Pictures, Revolution Studios, Chartoff
Productions and Winkler Films, and theatrically released by MGM Distribution Co.
in North America and 20th Century Fox internationally on December 20, 2006, sixteen years after
the release of Rocky V and thirty years after the release of the first film.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise for its screenplay, Stallone's performance, and heartfelt exploration of Balboa's character,
with many critics calling it a significant improvement over its predecessor, and many labelling the film one of the best entries in the franchise.
It was also a commercial success, grossing $156 million worldwide.
A spin-off, Creed, was released in 2015 and started its own series.
The film explores themes of philadelphia, pennsylvania,
transporter, love of one's life, fight, tombstone.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.